var data = [
    {
        question: "Which is the biggest unit of data storage in the following list?",
        options: ["Kilobyte","Gigabyte","Megabyte","Byte"],
        correct_option: "Gigabyte"
    },
    {
        question: "Speed of computer is measured in...",
        options: ["Hertz","Liter","Meter","Watt"],
        correct_option: "Hertz"
    },
    {
        question: "A DVD Reader reads...",
        options: ["Hard Disk","DVD Rom","Flash Memory","All of above"],
        correct_option: "DVD Rom"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the device which converts a picture on paper to an electronic image on the computer?",
        options: ["Printer","Scanner","Photo-relay","Ultra mouse"],
        correct_option: "Scanner"
    },
    {
        question: "Which device is used to generate an image on a paper from the computer?",
        options: ["Scanner","Printer","Mouse","Monitor"],
        correct_option: "Printer"
    },
    {
        question: "The brain of any computer system is",
        options: ["ALU","Memory","CPU","Control unit"],
        correct_option: "CPU"
    },
    {
        question: "What difference does the 5th generation computer have from other generation computers?",
        options: ["Technological advancement","Scientific code","Object Oriented Programming","All of the above"],
        correct_option: "Technological advancement"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following computer language is used for artificial intelligence?",
        options: ["FORTRAN","PROLOG","C","COBOL"],
        correct_option: "PROLOG"
    },
    {
        question: "The binary system uses powers of",
        options: ["2","10","8","16"],
        correct_option: "2"
    },
    {
        question: "A computer program that converts assembly language to machine language is",
        options: ["Compiler","Interpreter","Assembler","Comparator"],
        correct_option: "Assembler"
    },
    {
        question: "Any type of storage that is used for holding information between steps in its processing is",
        options: ["CPU","Primary storage","Intermediate storage","Internal storage"],
        correct_option: "Intermediate storage"
    },
    {
        question: "The term referring to evacuating the content of some part of the machine is known as",
        options: ["Dump","Enhancement","Down","Compiler"],
        correct_option: "Dump"
    },
    {
        question: "A single packet on a data link is known as",
        options: ["Path","Frame","Block","Group"],
        correct_option: "Frame"
    },
    {
        question: "The process of communicating with a file from a terminal is",
        options: ["Interactive","Interrogation","Heuristic","None of the above"],
        correct_option: "Interrogation"
    },
    {
        question: "A common boundary between two systems is called",
        options: ["Interdiction","Interface","Surface","None of the above"],
        correct_option: "Interface"
    },
    {
        question: "The examination and changing of single bits or small groups of his within a word is called",
        options: ["Bit","Byte","Bit manipulation","Bit slice"],
        correct_option: "Bit manipulation"
    },
    {
        question: "Which computer has been designed to be as compact as possible?",
        options: ["Mini","Super computer","Micro computer","Mainframe"],
        correct_option: "Micro computer"
    },
    {
        question: "The symbols used in an assembly language are",
        options: ["Codes","Mnemonics","Assembler","None of the above"],
        correct_option: "Mnemonics"
    },
    {
        question: "ASCII stands for",
        options: ["American standard code for information interchange","All purpose scientific code for information interchange","American security code for information interchange","American Scientific code for information interchange"],
        correct_option: "American standard code for information interchange"
    },
    {
        question: "Which device of computer operation dispenses with the use of the keyboard?",
        options: ["Joystick","Light pen","Mouse","Touch"],
        correct_option: "Mouse"
    },
    {
        question: "A program that is employed in the development, repair or enhancement of other programs is known as",
        options: ["System software","Software tool","Applications program","Utility program"],
        correct_option: "Software tool"
    },
    {
        question: "The list of coded instructions is called",
        options: ["Computer program","Algorithm","Flowchart","Utility programs"],
        correct_option: "Computer program"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is not an operating system?",
        options: ["Windows","Linux","Oracle","DOS"],
        correct_option: "Oracle"
    },
    {
        question: "When was the first operating system developed?",
        options: ["1948","1949","1950","1951"],
        correct_option: "1950"
    },
    {
        question: "What else is a command interpreter called?",
        options: ["prompt","kernel","shell","command"],
        correct_option: "shell"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the mean of the Booting in the operating system?",
        options: ["Restarting computer","Install the program","To scan","To turn off"],
        correct_option: "Restarting computer"
    },
    {
        question: "Banker's algorithm is used?",
        options: ["To prevent deadlock","For deadlock recovery","To solve the deadlock","None of these"],
        correct_option: "To prevent deadlock"
    },
    {
        question: "Which is true about Linux operating system?",
        options: ["Private operating system","Windows operating system","Open-source operating system","None of these"],
        correct_option: "Open-source operating system"
    },
    {
        question: "What is bootstrapping called?",
        options: ["Cold boot","Cold hot boot","Cold hot strap","Hot boot"],
        correct_option: "Cold boot"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is a single-user operating system?",
        options: ["Windows","MAC","Ms-Dos","None of these"],
        correct_option: "Ms-Dos"
    },
    {
        question: "The size of virtual memory is based on which of the following?",
        options: ["CPU","RAM","Address bus","Data bus"],
        correct_option: "Address bus"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is not application software?",
        options: ["Windows 7","WordPad","Photoshop","MS-excel"],
        correct_option: "Windows 7"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following supports Windows 64 bit?",
        options: ["Window XP","Window 2000","Window 1998","None of these"],
        correct_option: "Window XP"
    },
    {
        question: "What is Microsoft window?",
        options: ["Operating system","Graphics program","Word Processing","Database program"],
        correct_option: "Operating system"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is an example of a Real Time Operating System?",
        options: ["MAC","MS-DOS","Windows 10","Process Control"],
        correct_option: "Process Control"
    },
    {
        question: "Which windows was introduced to My Computer?",
        options: ["Windows 10","Windows XP","Windows 95","Windows 98"],
        correct_option: "Windows 95"
    },
    {
        question: "Which program runs first after booting the computer and loading the GUI?",
        options: ["Desktop Manager","File Manager","Windows Explorer","Authentication"],
        correct_option: "Authentication"
    },
    {
        question: "Last step in running and preparing batch jobs is to",
        options: ["printout is returned","printout is started","printout is queued","printout is verified"],
        correct_option: "printout is returned"
    },
    {
        question: "Second step in running and preparing batch jobs is to",
        options: ["wait in the queue","store output","write on printed sheets","verify the work"],
        correct_option: "verify the work"
    },
    {
        question: "Which module gives control of the CPU to the process selected by the short-term scheduler?",
        options: ["dispatcher","interrupt","scheduler","none of the mentioned"],
        correct_option: "dispatcher"
    },
    {
        question: "The processes that are residing in main memory and are ready and waiting to execute are kept on a list called _____________",
        options: ["job queue","ready queue","execution queue","process queue"],
        correct_option: "ready queue"
    },
    {
        question: "The interval from the time of submission of a process to the time of completion is termed as ____________",
        options: ["waiting time","turnaround time","response time","throughput"],
        correct_option: "turnaround time"
    },
    {
        question: "Which scheduling algorithm allocates the CPU first to the process that requests the CPU first?",
        options: ["first-come, first-served scheduling","shortest job scheduling","priority scheduling","none of the mentioned"],
        correct_option: "first-come, first-served scheduling"
    },
    {
        question: "In priority scheduling algorithm ________",
        options: ["CPU is allocated to the process with highest priority","CPU is allocated to the process with lowest priority","Equal priority processes can not be scheduled","None of the mentioned"],
        correct_option: "CPU is allocated to the process with highest priority"
    },
    {
        question: "Which algorithm is defined in Time quantum?",
        options: ["shortest job scheduling algorithm","round robin scheduling algorithm","priority scheduling algorithm","multilevel queue scheduling algorithm"],
        correct_option: "round robin scheduling algorithm"
    },
    {
        question: "Process are classified into different groups in __________",
        options: ["shortest job scheduling algorithm","round robin scheduling algorithm","priority scheduling algorithm","multilevel queue scheduling algorithm"],
        correct_option: "multilevel queue scheduling algorithm"
    },
    {
        question: "Which one of the following can not be scheduled by the kernel?",
        options: ["kernel level thread","user level thread","process","none of the mentioned"],
        correct_option: "user level thread"
    },
    {
        question: "Choose one of the disadvantages of the priority scheduling algorithm?",
        options: ["it schedules in a very complex manner","its scheduling takes up a lot of time","it can lead to some low priority process waiting indefinitely for the CPU","none of the mentioned"],
        correct_option: "it can lead to some low priority process waiting indefinitely for the CPU"
    },
    {
        question: "What is ‘Aging’?",
        options: ["keeping track of cache contents","keeping track of what pages are currently residing in memory","keeping track of how many times a given page is referenced","increasing the priority of jobs to ensure termination in a finite time"],
        correct_option: "increasing the priority of jobs to ensure termination in a finite time"
    },
    {
        question: "A solution to the problem of indefinite blockage of low – priority processes is",
        options: ["Starvation","Wait queue","Aging","Ready queue"],
        correct_option: "Aging"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following condition is required for a deadlock to be possible?",
        options: ["mutual exclusion","a process may hold allocated resources while awaiting assignment of other resources","no resource can be forcibly removed from a process holding it","all of the mentioned"],
        correct_option: "all of the mentioned"
    },
    {
        question: "A system is in the safe state if _________",
        options: ["the system can allocate resources to each process in some order and still avoid a deadlock","there exist a safe sequence","all of the mentioned","none of the mentioned"],
        correct_option: "the system can allocate resources to each process in some order and still avoid a deadlock"
    },
    {
        question: "Which one of the following is the deadlock avoidance algorithm?",
        options: ["banker’s algorithm","round-robin algorithm","elevator algorithm","karn’s algorithm"],
        correct_option: "banker’s algorithm"
    },
    {
        question: "For an effective operating system, when to check for deadlock?",
        options: ["every time a resource request is made","at fixed time intervals","every time a resource request is made at fixed time intervals","none of the mentioned"],
        correct_option: "every time a resource request is made at fixed time intervals"
    },
    {
        question: "A problem encountered in multitasking when a process is perpetually denied necessary resources is called ____________",
        options: ["deadlock","starvation","inversion","aging"],
        correct_option: "starvation"
    },
    {
        question: "Which one of the following is a visual ( mathematical ) way to determine the deadlock occurrence?",
        options: ["resource allocation graph","starvation graph","inversion graph","none of the mentioned"],
        correct_option: "resource allocation graph"
    },
    {
        question: "To avoid deadlock _________",
        options: ["there must be a fixed number of resources to allocate","resource allocation must be done only once","all deadlocked processes must be aborted","inversion technique can be used"],
        correct_option: "there must be a fixed number of resources to allocate"
    },
    {
        question: "What is Cyber Security?",
        options: ["Cyber Security provides security against malware","Cyber Security provides security against cyber-terrorists","Cyber Security protects a system from cyber attacks","All of the mentioned"],
        correct_option: "All of the mentioned"
    },
    {
        question: "Who is the father of computer security?",
        options: ["August Kerckhoffs","Bob Thomas","Robert","Charles"],
        correct_option: "August Kerckhoffs"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is defined as an attempt to steal, spy, damage or destroy computer /n systems, networks, or their associated information?",
        options: ["Cyber attack","Computer security","Cryptography","Digital hacking"],
        correct_option: "Cyber attack"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is a disadvantage of cyber security?",
        options: ["Makes the system slower","Minimizes computer freezing and crashes","Gives privacy to users","Protects system against viruses"],
        correct_option: "Makes the system slower"
    },
    {
        question: "“Cyberspace” was coined by _______",
        options: ["Richard Stallman","William Gibson","Andrew Tannenbaum","Scott Fahlman"],
        correct_option: "William Gibson"
    },
    {
        question: "In which year has hacking become a practical crime and a matter of concern in the field of /n cyber technology?",
        options: ["1991","1983","1970","1964"],
        correct_option: "1970"
    },
    {
        question: "Governments hired some highly skilled hackers for providing cyber security for the country /n or state. These types of hackers are termed as _____ ",
        options: ["Nation / State sponsored hackers","CIA triad","Special Hackers","Government Hackers"],
        correct_option: "Nation / State sponsored hackers"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is the hacking approach where cyber-criminals design fake websites /n or pages for tricking or gaining additional traffic?",
        options: ["Pharming","Website-Duplication","Mimicking","Spamming"],
        correct_option: "Pharming"
    },
    {
        question: "A cyber-criminal or penetration tester uses the additional data that stores certain special /n instructions in the memory for activities to break the system in which of the following /n attack?",
        options: ["Clickjacking","Buffer-overflow","Phishing","MiTM"],
        correct_option: "Buffer-overflow"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following do Cyber attackers commonly target for fetching IP address of a /n target or victim user?",
        options: ["ip tracker","emails","websites","web pages"],
        correct_option: "websites"
    },
    {
        question: "They are nefarious hackers, and their main motive is to gain financial profit by doing /n cyber crimes. Who are “they” referred to here?",
        options: ["White Hat Hackers","Black Hat Hackers","Hactivists","Gray Hat Hackers"],
        correct_option: "Black Hat Hackers"
    },
    {
        question: "Where did the term “hacker” originate?",
        options: ["MIT(Massachusetts Institute of Technology)","New York University","Harvard University","Bell’s Lab"],
        correct_option: "MIT(Massachusetts Institute of Technology)"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the existence of weakness in a system or network is known as?",
        options: ["Attack","Exploit","Vulnerability","Threat"],
        correct_option: "Vulnerability"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is an internet scam done by cyber-criminals where the user is /n convinced digitally to provide confidential information?",
        options: ["MiTM attack","Phishing attack","Website attack","DoS attack"],
        correct_option: "Phishing attack"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following term refers to a group of hackers who are both white and black hat?",
        options: ["Yellow Hat hackers","Grey Hat hackers","Red Hat Hackers","White-Black Hat Hackers"],
        correct_option: "Grey Hat hackers"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following DDoS in mobile systems wait for the owner to trigger the cyber attack?",
        options: ["botnets","programs","virus","worms"],
        correct_option: "botnets"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is the least strong security encryption standard?",
        options: ["WPA3","WPA2","WPA","WEP"],
        correct_option: "WEP"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following statements define Computer Graphics?",
        options: ["It refers to designing plans","It means designing computers","It refers to designing images","None of the mentioned"],
        correct_option: "It refers to designing images"
    },
    {
        question: "Among the given scientists/inventor who is known as the father of Computer Graphics?",
        options: ["Nikola Tesla","Ivan Sutherland","Ada Lovelace","Marie Curie"],
        correct_option: "Ivan Sutherland"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is a Computer Graphics Curve?",
        options: ["Bezier Curves","Implicit Curves","Explicit Curves","All of the above"],
        correct_option: "All of the above"
    },
    {
        question: "Who is the first user of computer graphics?",
        options: ["William Fetter","Ivan Edward Sutherland","Ada Lovelace","Nicholas Williams"],
        correct_option: "William Fetter"
    },
    {
        question: "Curves in computer graphics is primarily used for which of the following function?",
        options: ["To draw different types of objects onto the screen","Zooming out a picture","Copying a picture","Zooming in a picture"],
        correct_option: "To draw different types of objects onto the screen"
    },
    {
        question: "_________ types of translation are present in computer graphics",
        options: ["5","3","4","6"],
        correct_option: "3"
    },
    {
        question: "Bitmap is a collection of ____________ that describes an image",
        options: ["pixels","algorithms","bits","colors"],
        correct_option: "pixels"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following operations can be used to zoom in or out around any axis on a /n three-dimensional object from its original position?",
        options: ["Rotation","Shearing","Scaling","Translation"],
        correct_option: "Scaling"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is defined as the drawing of number of copies of the same image in /n rows and columns across the interface window so that they cover the entire window? ",
        options: ["Zooming","Panning","Tiling","Roaming"],
        correct_option: "Tiling"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following algorithm is a faster method for calculating pixel positions?",
        options: ["Parallel line algorithm","Mid-point algorithm","DDA line algorithm","Bresenham’s line algorithm"],
        correct_option: "DDA line algorithm"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is a correct abbreviation of DDA algorithm?",
        options: ["Data differential analyzer","Direct differential analyzer","Digital difference analyzer","Digital differential analyzer"],
        correct_option: "Digital differential analyzer"
    },
    {
        question: "In which of the following method, fixed pattern of a line is used to generate characters?",
        options: ["Dot-matrix method","Bitmap method","Stroke method","Starbust method"],
        correct_option: "Starbust method"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following device is designed to minimize the background sound?",
        options: ["Joystick","Data glove","Microphone","Digitizers"],
        correct_option: "Microphone"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following process is analogous to creating a view of a three dimensional /n scene?",
        options: ["Making a painting","Taking a photograph","Recording a sound","Editing a picture"],
        correct_option: "Taking a photograph"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following step involves in placing the object into appropriate position within /n the scene using their world coordinates?",
        options: ["Modelling Transformation","Viewing Transformation","Projection Transformation","Viewport Transformation"],
        correct_option: "Modelling Transformation"
    },
    {
        question: "Aspect Ratio can be defined as -",
        options: ["The ratio of the vertical points to horizontal points","of pixels","Both (a) and (b)","None of the above"],
        correct_option: "The ratio of the vertical points to horizontal points"
    },
    {
        question: "Shadow mask method is used in -",
        options: ["Raster scan system","Random scan system","Both (a) & (b)","None of the above"],
        correct_option: "Raster scan system"
    },
    {
        question: "Plasma panel is also called as -",
        options: ["Non-emissive display","Liquid crystal display","Gas discharge display","None of the above"],
        correct_option: "Gas discharge display"
    },
    {
        question: "Network layer firewall works as a _______",
        options: ["Frame filter","Packet filter","Content filter","Virus filter"],
        correct_option: "Packet filter"
    },
    {
        question: "A firewall is installed at the point where the secure internal network and untrusted /n external network meet which is also known as ________ ",
        options: ["Chock point","Meeting point","Firewall point","Secure point"],
        correct_option: "Chock point"
    },
    {
        question: "A firewall needs to be __________ so that it can grow proportionally with the network that /n it protects.",
        options: ["Robust","Expansive","Fast","Scalable"],
        correct_option: "Expansive"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is private IP address?",
        options: ["12.0.0.1","168.172.19.39","172.15.14.36","192.168.24.43"],
        correct_option: "192.168.24.43"
    },
    {
        question: "Which class of IP address provides a maximum of only 254 host addresses per network ID?",
        options: ["class A","class B","class C","class D"],
        correct_option: "class C"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following are layers in the TCP/IP model? /n Application /n Session /n transport /n Internet /n Data link /n Physical",
        options: ["1 and 2","1, 3 and 4","2, 3 and 5","3, 4 and 5"],
        correct_option: "1, 3 and 4"
    },
    {
        question: "Which layer 4 protocol is used for a Telnet connection?",
        options: ["IP","TCP","TCP/IP","UDP"],
        correct_option: "TCP"
    },
    {
        question: "How long is an IPv6 address?",
        options: ["32 bits","128 bits","64 bits","128 bits"],
        correct_option: "128 bits"
    },
    {
        question: "What is a stub network?",
        options: ["A network with more than one exit point","A network with more than one exit and entry point.","A network with only one entry and no exit point","A network that has only one entry and exit point"],
        correct_option: "A network that has only one entry and exit point"
    },
    {
        question: "What is Cloud Computing?",
        options: ["Cloud Computing means providing services like storage, servers, database, networking etc","Cloud Computing means storing data in a database","Cloud Computing is a tool used to create an application","None of the mentioned"],
        correct_option: "Cloud Computing means providing services like storage, servers, database, networking"
    },
    {
        question: "Who is the father of cloud computing?",
        options: ["Sharon B. Codd","Edgar Frank Codd","J.C.R. Licklider","Charles Bachman"],
        correct_option: "J.C.R. Licklider"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following are the features of cloud computing?",
        options: ["Security","Availability","Large Network Access","All of the mentioned"],
        correct_option: "All of the mentioned"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is a type of cloud computing service?",
        options: ["Service-as-a-Software (SaaS)","Software-and-a-Server (SaaS)","Software-as-a-Service (SaaS)","Software-as-a-Server (SaaS)"],
        correct_option: "Software-as-a-Service (SaaS)"
    },
    {
        question: "Which architectural layer is used as a backend in cloud computing?",
        options: ["cloud","soft","client","all of the mentioned"],
        correct_option: "cloud"
    },
    {
        question: "All cloud computing applications suffer from the inherent _______ that is intrinsic in /n their WAN connectivity",
        options: ["noise","propagation","latency","all of the mentioned"],
        correct_option: "latency"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following architectural standards is working with cloud computing industry?",
        options: ["Web-application frameworks","Service-oriented architecture","Standardized Web services","All of the mentioned"],
        correct_option: "Service-oriented architecture"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is the wrong statement about cloud computing?",
        options: ["Private cloud doesn’t employ the same level of virtualization","Data center operates under average loads","Private cloud doesn’t pooling of resources that a cloud computing provider can achieve","Abstraction enables the key benefit of cloud computing: shared, ubiquitous access"],
        correct_option: "Private cloud doesn’t employ the same level of virtualization"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is required by Cloud Computing?",
        options: ["That the identity be authenticated","That the authentication be portable","That you establish an identity","All of the mentioned"],
        correct_option: "All of the mentioned"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is the Cloud Platform provided by Amazon?",
        options: ["AWS","Cloudera","Azure","All of the mentioned"],
        correct_option: "AWS"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is the most refined and restrictive cloud service model?",
        options: ["PaaS","IaaS","SaaS","CaaS"],
        correct_option: "PaaS"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is not a property of cloud computing?",
        options: ["virtualization","composability","scalability","all of the mentioned"],
        correct_option: "composability"
    },
    {
        question: "Which is the most essential concept related to Cloud computing?",
        options: ["Abstraction","Reliability","Productivity","All of the mentioned"],
        correct_option: "Abstraction"
    },
    {
        question: "What is Digital Image Processing?",
        options: ["It’s an application that alters digital videos","It’s a software that allows altering digital pictures","It’s a system that manipulates digital medias","It’s a machine that allows altering digital images"],
        correct_option: "It’s a software that allows altering digital pictures"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following process helps in Image enhancement?",
        options: ["Digital Image Processing","Analog Image Processing","Both a and b","None of the above"],
        correct_option: "Both a and b"
    },
    {
        question: "Among the following, functions that can be performed by digital image processing is?",
        options: ["Fast image storage and retrieval","Controlled viewing","Image reformatting","All of the above"],
        correct_option: "All of the above"
    },
    {
        question: "What are the categories of digital image processing?",
        options: ["Image Enhancement","Image Classification and Analysis","Image Transformation","All of the mentioned"],
        correct_option: "All of the mentioned"
    },
    {
        question: "How does picture formation in the eye vary from image formation in a camera?",
        options: ["Fixed focal length","Varying distance between lens and imaging plane","No difference","Variable focal length"],
        correct_option: "Variable focal length"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following statement describe the term pixel depth?",
        options: ["It is the number of units used to represent each pixel in RGB space","It is the number of mm used to represent each pixel in RGB space","It is the number of bytes used to represent each pixel in RGB space","It is the number of bits used to represent each pixel in RGB space"],
        correct_option: "It is the number of bits used to represent each pixel in RGB space"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is the first and foremost step in Image Processing?",
        options: ["Image acquisition","Segmentation","Image enhancement","Image restoration"],
        correct_option: "Image acquisition"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is the next step in image processing after compression?",
        options: ["Representation and description","Morphological processing","Segmentation","Wavelets"],
        correct_option: "Morphological processing"
    },
    {
        question: "_________ determines the quality of a digital image",
        options: ["The discrete gray levels","The number of samples","discrete gray levels & number of samples","None of the mentioned"],
        correct_option: "discrete gray levels & number of samples"
    },
    {
        question: "Image processing involves how many steps?",
        options: ["7","8","13","10"],
        correct_option: "10"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following tool is used in tasks such as zooming, shrinking, rotating, etc.?",
        options: ["Filters","Sampling","Interpolation","None of the Mentioned"],
        correct_option: "Interpolation"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following in an image can be removed by using a smoothing filter?",
        options: ["Sharp transitions of brightness levels","Sharp transitions of gray levels","Smooth transitions of gray levels","Smooth transitions of brightness levels"],
        correct_option: "Sharp transitions of gray levels"
    },
    {
        question: "Gamma Correction is defined as _________",
        options: ["Light brightness variation","A Power-law response phenomenon","Inverted Intensity curve","None of the Mentioned"],
        correct_option: "A Power-law response phenomenon"
    },
]

export default data;